LAURA BERMUDEZ GARCIA

Kirkland, WA 98034

Phone: 2069729255 | Email: laurabermudezg@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/laura-bermudez-garcia/ | Github:

https://github.com/lbeagleeyes | Portfolio: https://lbeagleeyes.github.io/Portfolio-LauraBermudez/

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, 10 years of experience, recently graduated from a Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp at the University of Washington, fully bilingual English/Spanish, interested in complete software development life cycle, passionate about user-centered design, with programming skills in C/C++, .Net, and SQL, using agile methodologies. Able to work as a liaison between technical and non-technical teams due to excellent communication skills, experience gathering requirements and mock-up design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C/C++, C#.Net, Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, REACT, html, css, SQL, MongoDB

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer / Systems Analyst Intel Corporation

08/2011 – 09/2014

San Jose, Costa Rica

- Net C# developer for a data analysis tool that logs tens of thousands of data at a second interval in more than 200 MS SQL and IIS web servers across continents with a user interface that enables data visualization for monitoring and analysis through graphing, playing live data, and information share
- .Net C# (HTML5, MVC, Javascript, JQuery) developer for fab construction project that consolidates 3 applications in one to improve customer's productivity and user experience.
- As a systems analyst, gathered requirements, developed mock-ups and created user stories to improve communication between customers and developers while using Agile Methodologies and Kanban to plan, track and prioritize work daily.
- Key Accomplishments: Winner of a Division Recognition Award (DRA)

Software Developer

12/2009 – 07/2011

Desert Development Company

San Jose, Costa Rica

- C++ software developer for a new games suite making good use of design patterns and SCRUM methodology.
- Developed frameworks in C++ for server and in Actionscript 3.0 for flash client that significantly increased development productivity.

Software Engineer Western Union

04/2007 - 02/2010

San Jose, Costa Rica

- Coordinator between teams to deliver new releases worldwide, gathering requirements from different regions to design and develop new features using C/C++ with MFC, ASP and SQL Server technologies for core business money transfer software distribution system.
- *Key Accomplishments*: Winner of a quarterly award for excellent teamwork during a national Money Transfer software roll out for US and Canada.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer02-2006- 03-2007Align TechnologySan Jose, Costa Rica

Software Quality Engineer 07-2005– 02-2006 Avantica Technologies San Jose, Costa Rica

Teaching Experience07-2004- 06-2007University of Costa RicaSan Jose, Costa Rica

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp: University of Washington, Seattle, WA. 2019 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Software Product Management Certificate: University of Washington, Bellevue, WA. 2017-2018

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science: University of Costa Rica, San Jose, Costa Rica. 2004